ottsworld.com 2018-10-29

# Ottsworld Privacy and Disclosure Policy • Ottsworld Unique Travel Experiences

## Privacy Policy

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally Identifiable Information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as described in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read my privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how I collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with my website.

### What personal information do I collect from the people that visit my blog?

When registering for a newsletter or contest on the site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address or other details to help you with your experience.

### When do I collect information?

I collect information from you when you subscribe to a newsletter or enter information on my site.

### How do I use your information?

I may use the information I collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for my newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

  *     * To send periodic emails regarding updates, products, and services.
    * To personalize user’s experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.
    * To improve the website in order to better serve you.
    * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.

### How do I protect your information?

This website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit as safe as possible.  I only provide articles and information. I never ask for credit card numbers.  I use regular Malware Scanning.

I do use an SSL certificate however at this time I only provide articles and information. I never ask for personal or private information like names, email addresses, or credit card numbers.

### Does Ottsworld use ‘cookies’?

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, I use cookies to help me remember and understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables me to provide you with improved services. I also use cookies to help compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that I can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

I use cookies to compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. I may also use trusted third-party services that track this information on my behalf.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Since browser is a little different, look at your browser’s Help Menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you turn cookies off, Some of the features that make your site experience more efficient may not function properly. It won’t affect the user’s experience that make your site experience more efficient and may not function properly.

### Third-party disclosure

I do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your Personally Identifiable Information unless I provide users with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist me in operating my website, conducting my business, or serving my users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. I may also release information when it’s release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce my site policies, or protect my or others’ rights, property or safety.

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

### Third-party links

Occasionally, at my discretion, I may include or offer third-party products or services on my website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. I therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, I seek to protect the integrity of my site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

### Google

Google’s advertising requirements can be summed up by Google’s Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en

**I have not enabled Google AdSense on our site but we may do so in the future.**

### California Online Privacy Protection Act

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require any person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting Personally Identifiable Information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals or companies with whom it is being shared. – See more at: http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf

According to CalOPPA, I agree to the following:  
Users can visit my site anonymously.  
Once this privacy policy is created, I will add a link to it on our home page or as a minimum, on the first significant page after entering our website.  
MyPrivacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can easily be found on the page specified above.

You will be notified of any Privacy Policy changes:  
• On my Privacy Policy Page  
Can change your personal information:  
• By emailing me

How does my site handle Do Not Track signals?  
I honor Do Not Track signals and Do Not Track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?  
It’s also important to note that we do not allow third-party behavioral tracking

### COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under the age of 13 years old, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, United States’ consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

**I do not specifically market to children under the age of 13 years old.**

### Fair Information Practices

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices I will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:  
Iwill notify you via email  
• Within 7 business days

I also agree to the Individual Redress Principle which requires that individuals have the right to legally pursue enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

### CAN SPAM Act

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

I collect your email address in order to:  
• Market to my mailing list

To be in accordance with CANSPAM, I agree to the following:  
• Not use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.  
• Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.  
• Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.  
• Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.  
• Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.  
• Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can email me at  
• Follow the instructions at the bottom of each email.  
and I will promptly remove you from ALL correspondence.

## Disclosure Policy

### Partnerships

From time to time, A Ottsworld works with travel brands and tourism boards in order to experience and promote specific destinations, tours, activities, etc. Sometimes I receive compensation as part of these partnerships, which can take the form of cash, credit, or free activities, tours, gear, accommodation, flights, etc.

However, all opinions expressed on this site are mine and I provide fair, unbiased reviews.  I will tell you if I don’t like something! When I partner with a brand or tourism board, I still retain complete editorial control. I also never work with brands that I do not believe in or support – anything I recommend to you, I would (and do) use myself.

All such partnerships/exchanges are disclosed in each and every relevant blog post.

### Affiliate links

In some instances, I may include affiliate links in posts where I recommend specific gear, tours, or activities. If you purchase something through one of my affiliate links, I receive a small commission at no extra cost to you. These links are always disclosed.

Among other programs, A Ottsworld is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites.

## Contacting Ottsworld

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, you may contact us using the information below.

www.ottsworld.com  
456 Logan St. Apt 301  
Denver, CO 80203  
USA  
info@Ottsworld.com

Last Edited on 2018-05-28
